[
  {
    "question": "Which of these people was born the same year as Queen Elizabeth II?",
    "answer1": "Marilyn Monroe",
    "answer2": "Elizabeth Taylor",
    "answer3": "Judy Garland",
    "answer4": "Audrey Hepburn",
    "correctAnswer": "Marilyn Monroe"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what language was Anne Frank's original diary first published?",
    "answer1": "Dutch",
    "answer2": "English",
    "answer3": "German",
    "answer4": "French",
    "correctAnswer": "Dutch"
  },
  {
    "question": "What insect shorted out an early supercomputer and inspired the term \"computer bug\"?",
    "answer1": "Moth",
    "answer2": "Fly",
    "answer3": "Ladybug",
    "answer4": "Japanese beetle",
    "correctAnswer": "Moth"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the children's book series, where is Paddington Bear originally from?",
    "answer1": "Peru",
    "answer2": "England",
    "answer3": "India",
    "answer4": "Canada",
    "correctAnswer": "Peru"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many days make up a non-leap year in the Islamic calendar?",
    "answer1": "354",
    "answer2": "365",
    "answer3": "472",
    "answer4": "412",
    "correctAnswer": "354"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the Population Reference Bureau, what is the approximate number of people who have ever lived on earth?",
    "answer1": "100 billion",
    "answer2": "50 billion",
    "answer3": "1 trillion",
    "answer4": "5 trillion",
    "correctAnswer": "100 billion"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Nephelococcygia\" is the practice of doing what?",
    "answer1": "Finding shapes in clouds",
    "answer2": "Breaking glass with your voice",
    "answer3": "Swimming in freezing water",
    "answer4": "Sleeping with your eyes open",
    "correctAnswer": "Finding shapes in clouds"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a failed assassination attempt, what U.S. president was shot twice at point-blank range, but survived because both guns misfired?",
    "answer1": "Andrew Jackson",
    "answer2": "John Adams",
    "answer3": "James Polk",
    "answer4": "Martin Van Buren",
    "correctAnswer": "Andrew Jackson"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these religious observances lasts for the shortest period of time during the calendar year?",
    "answer1": "Diwali",
    "answer2": "Ramadan",
    "answer3": "Lent",
    "answer4": "Hanukkah",
    "correctAnswer": "Diwali"
  },
  {
    "question": "Continents shift at the same rate as what?",
    "answer1": "Growing fingernails",
    "answer2": "Menstrual cycles",
    "answer3": "Children grow",
    "answer4": "People have birthdays",
    "correctAnswer": "Growing fingernails"
  },
  {
    "question": "Saint Valentine is the patron saint of which specific disease?",
    "answer1": "Epilepsy",
    "answer2": "Cancer",
    "answer3": "Lyme disease",
    "answer4": "Plague",
    "correctAnswer": "Epilepsy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two countries took part in the \"Turbot War\" dispute between 1994 and 1996?",
    "answer1": "Spain and Canada",
    "answer2": "France and UK",
    "answer3": "Spain and Portugal",
    "answer4": "Brazil and Argentina",
    "correctAnswer": "Spain and Canada"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2007, which comedian jumped from the roof of Cannes' Carlton Hotel wearing a giant bee costume?",
    "answer1": "Jerry Seinfeld",
    "answer2": "Tina Fey",
    "answer3": "Seth Meyers",
    "answer4": "Jimmy Fallon",
    "correctAnswer": "Jerry Seinfeld"
  },
  {
    "question": "The adjective \"cutaneous\" relates to which part of the human body?",
    "answer1": "Skin",
    "answer2": "Bones",
    "answer3": "Muscles",
    "answer4": "Hair",
    "correctAnswer": "Skin"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the oldest building in New York City?",
    "answer1": "Wyckoff House",
    "answer2": "Staats House",
    "answer3": "Bronck House",
    "answer4": "Bowne House",
    "correctAnswer": "Wyckoff House"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which architect designed the Woolworth Building in New York City?",
    "answer1": "Gilbert Cass",
    "answer2": "Daniel Burnham",
    "answer3": "Philip Johnson",
    "answer4": "I.M. Pei",
    "correctAnswer": "Gilbert Cass"
  },
  {
    "question": "At which hospital did the first heart transplant take place?",
    "answer1": "Groote Schuur Hospital",
    "answer2": "Charité-Universitätsmedizin Berlin",
    "answer3": "Karolinska Universitetssjukhuset",
    "answer4": "Aarhus Universitetshospital",
    "correctAnswer": "Groote Schuur Hospital"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ken Thompson and Dennis Ritchie co-created which operating system?",
    "answer1": "Unix",
    "answer2": "Linux",
    "answer3": "Solaris",
    "answer4": "BSD",
    "correctAnswer": "Unix"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who discovered the life or death importance of washing hands while studying maternity wards?",
    "answer1": "Ignaz Semmelweis",
    "answer2": "Torsten Wiesel",
    "answer3": "Robert Lefkowitz",
    "answer4": "Baruj Benacerraf",
    "correctAnswer": "Ignaz Semmelweis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of Alexander the Great's horse?",
    "answer1": "Bucephalus",
    "answer2": "Marengo",
    "answer3": "Arbitan",
    "answer4": "Barbaros",
    "correctAnswer": "Bucephalus"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Caldecott Medal is an award given in what field?",
    "answer1": "Children's book illustrations",
    "answer2": "Furniture design",
    "answer3": "Astrophysics",
    "answer4": "Motor sports",
    "correctAnswer": "Children's book illustrations"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1998 movie \"The Man in the Iron Mask\", which character dies defending Philippe?",
    "answer1": "D'Artagnan",
    "answer2": "Athos",
    "answer3": "Aramis",
    "answer4": "Porthos",
    "correctAnswer": "D'Artagnan"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Soviet operation forced over 2,000 scientists and engineers to relocate from East Germany to Russia to work on missile design and production?",
    "answer1": "Operation Osoaviakhim",
    "answer2": "Operation Samland",
    "answer3": "Operation Kutuzov",
    "answer4": "Operation Iskra",
    "correctAnswer": "Operation Osoaviakhim"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which school's football players run onto the field behind \"Ralphie\", a live bison?",
    "answer1": "University of Colorado",
    "answer2": "University of Miami",
    "answer3": "University of Wisconsin",
    "answer4": "Washington University",
    "correctAnswer": "University of Colorado"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which star of \"Cheers\" also starred in the TV show \"Veronica's Closet\"?",
    "answer1": "Kirstie Alley",
    "answer2": "Shelley Long",
    "answer3": "Rhea Perlmann",
    "answer4": "Kelsey Grammer",
    "correctAnswer": "Kirstie Alley"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cricket stars Clyde Walcott, Everton Weekes and Frank Worrell were all born in which city within 18 months of each other?",
    "answer1": "Bridgetown, Barbados",
    "answer2": "Hamilton, Canada",
    "answer3": "Lancaster, Pennsylvania",
    "answer4": "Jalapa, Guatemala",
    "correctAnswer": "Bridgetown, Barbados"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played the role of David Duchovny's daughter on the TV show \"Californication\"?",
    "answer1": "Madeleine Martin",
    "answer2": "Natascha McElhone",
    "answer3": "Madeline Zima",
    "answer4": "Addison Timlin",
    "correctAnswer": "Madeleine Martin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Beards were once taxed by what famous 17th-century ruler?",
    "answer1": "Peter the Great",
    "answer2": "Louis XIV",
    "answer3": "Philip IV",
    "answer4": "Charles III",
    "correctAnswer": "Peter the Great"
  },
  {
    "question": "What comic strip was set in the Okeefenokee Swamp?",
    "answer1": "Pogo",
    "answer2": "The Far Side",
    "answer3": "Calvin and Hobbes",
    "answer4": "Captain Kate",
    "correctAnswer": "Pogo"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Betty Rubble's maiden name?",
    "answer1": "McBricker",
    "answer2": "McAdams",
    "answer3": "McLean",
    "answer4": "McDaniel",
    "correctAnswer": "McBricker"
  },
  {
    "question": "What company introduced the first radio with push-button tuning in 1927?",
    "answer1": "Zenith",
    "answer2": "Hublot",
    "answer3": "Rolex",
    "answer4": "Panerai",
    "correctAnswer": "Zenith"
  },
  {
    "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Gaslight\"?",
    "answer1": "Angela Lansbury",
    "answer2": "Maggie Smith",
    "answer3": "Tom Bosley",
    "answer4": "Angela Lansbury",
    "correctAnswer": "Angela Lansbury"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the Oscar for Best Director for the 1987 film \"The Last Emperor\"?",
    "answer1": "Bernardo Bertolucci",
    "answer2": "Pier Paolo Pasolini",
    "answer3": "Sergio Leone",
    "answer4": "Vittorio Storaro",
    "correctAnswer": "Bernardo Bertolucci"
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did Joseph Merrick, also known as Elephant Man, die?",
    "answer1": "1890",
    "answer2": "1907",
    "answer3": "1931",
    "answer4": "1869",
    "correctAnswer": "1890"
  },
  {
    "question": "The first vending machines in England dispensed what?",
    "answer1": "Postcards",
    "answer2": "Soft drinks",
    "answer3": "Cigarettes",
    "answer4": "Coffee",
    "correctAnswer": "Postcards"
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was the first black hole discovered?",
    "answer1": "1971",
    "answer2": "1966",
    "answer3": "1952",
    "answer4": "1980",
    "correctAnswer": "1971"
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of animal attacked Jimmy Carter during an April 1979 fishing trip?",
    "answer1": "A rabbit",
    "answer2": "A badger",
    "answer3": "An otter",
    "answer4": "A mink",
    "correctAnswer": "A rabbit"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the \"Davy Lamp\" commonly referred to as?",
    "answer1": "Miner's lamp",
    "answer2": "Buffer lamp",
    "answer3": "Tripod lamp",
    "answer4": "Piano lamp",
    "correctAnswer": "Miner's lamp"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Yehudi Menuhin's main profession?",
    "answer1": "Violinist",
    "answer2": "Pianist",
    "answer3": "Singer",
    "answer4": "Cellist",
    "correctAnswer": "Violinist"
  },
  {
    "question": "This singer/musician was just fifteen years old when he joined the Spencer Davis Group and later had two number one hits on the Billboard Hot 100?",
    "answer1": "Steve Winwood",
    "answer2": "Jim Capaldi",
    "answer3": "Ginger Baker",
    "answer4": "Jeff Lynne",
    "correctAnswer": "Steve Winwood"
  }
]

